Compared to other large mammals on Earth, we humans have relatively little hair.
与地球上的其他大型哺乳动物相比，我们人类的毛发相对较少。
This obvious fact is not so strange until we look at our closest living relatives in the animal kingdom — chimpanzees and other great apes.
这个显而易见的事实并没有什么奇怪的，直到我们看到动物王国中与我们关系最密切的现存近亲——黑猩猩和其他大型猿类。
Why, might we ask, have we evolved to be almost hairless when all other primates are still covered in fur?
我们不禁要问，为什么当所有其他灵长类动物仍然浑身覆盖着毛发时，我们却进化得几乎没有毛发了呢？
In fact, bizarre as it may seem, our lack of hair has been the key to our evolutionary success as a species.
事实上，尽管这可能看起来很离奇，但我们毛发的缺失却是我们作为一个物种在进化上取得成功的关键。
The question why our earliest ancestors lost their hair when fur would have been beneficial to them — for keeping warm on cold nights, for example — was pondered by Charles Darwin, the famous evolutionist: "No one supposes that the nakedness of the skin is any direct advantage to man."
我们最早的祖先为什么会在毛发对他们有益的时候（比如在寒冷的夜晚保暖）失去毛发，这个问题曾被著名的进化论者查尔斯·达尔文思考过：“没有人认为皮肤裸露对人类有任何直接的好处。”
He concluded that the reason hominins lost their hair was sexual selection.
他得出的结论是，原始人类失去毛发的原因是性选择。
In other words, we prefer our partners to have little hair.
换句话说，我们更倾向于选择毛发较少的伴侣。
But what caused our ancestors to start losing their hair before this preference set in?
但是，是什么导致我们的祖先在这种偏好形成之前就开始失去毛发了呢？
The most likely hypothesis to explain the loss of hair is that it became necessary when early hominids moved to a more open savannah habitat around 2 to 3 million years ago, when they started to hunt big game.
解释毛发缺失最有可能的假设是，大约在200万到300万年前，早期原始人类迁移到更开阔的草原栖息地，开始捕猎大型猎物时，毛发的缺失就变得有必要了。
Hunting in open savannah meant being exposed to the strong heat of the sun for several hours in the day and being in danger of overheating.
在开阔的草原上狩猎意味着每天要暴露在强烈的阳光下几个小时，并且有过热的危险。
Being covered in hair prevented our ancestors from losing heat fast enough.
浑身覆盖着毛发会阻碍我们的祖先足够快地散热。
So, as Peter Wheeler, of Liverpool John Moores University in the UK, explained, losing hair allowed them to develop the ability to sweat and therefore to cool down.
所以，正如英国利物浦约翰摩尔大学的彼得·惠勒所解释的那样，失去毛发使他们能够发展出汗的能力，从而降温。
Early humans could, as a consequence, be out at midday hunting and foraging.
因此，早期人类可以在正午时分外出狩猎和觅食。
"It would be [an] enormous advantage to be able to spend the entire midday foraging, finding mates or fighting enemies", Tamás Dávid-Barrett of Oxford University says.
牛津大学的塔马斯·大卫－巴雷特说：“能够在整个正午时分觅食、寻找伴侣或与敌人战斗，这将是一个巨大的优势。”
"Sweating allows that, and for sweat to be efficient you need to be mostly hairless".
“出汗使这成为可能，而且为了让出汗更有效率，你需要几乎没有毛发。”
The meat from hunting animals gave early humans the energy to fuel their growing brain.
狩猎动物获得的肉为早期人类提供了能量，促进了他们大脑的发育。
Humans are the sweatiest primates on Earth.
人类是地球上出汗最多的灵长类动物。
They have up to 5 million sweat glands, which produce about 12 litres of sweat per day.
人类拥有多达500万个汗腺，每天大约能产生12升汗水。
It's this propensity to sweat that accounts for our hairlessness and has allowed us to thrive.
正是这种出汗的倾向解释了我们毛发缺失的原因，并使我们得以繁衍兴旺。
It might help to remember this next time you're surrounded by sweaty hairless torsos in the gym!
下次当你在健身房里被汗流浃背、没有毛发的身躯包围时，记住这一点可能会有所帮助！